matildajaneclothing.com 2019-01-07

# Online Privacy Policy

**Matilda Jane Clothing**  
**Website Privacy Policy**

Matilda Jane Clothing (“we,” “us,” “our”) is committed to protecting the privacy of your information. We operate websites which follow industry standards in helping to assure the privacy of our websites’ visitors. All information we collect, including through transactions and all correspondence, are handled with discretion and care. The Privacy Policy below sets forth our policies and practices regarding the collection, use, and disclosure of the information we receive through your use and navigation of all of the websites Matilda Jane Clothing owns and operates (collectively, the “Sites”). 

**Effective Date**

This Privacy Policy is effective as of January 5, 2017.

**Last Updated**

This Privacy Policy was last updated on February 7, 2018. 

**_Scope_**

This Privacy Policy applies to the Sites, which include [www.matildajaneclothing.com](https://www.matildajaneclothing.com/), its subdomains, and all of the websites and Internet properties owned or operated by Matilda Jane Clothing, regardless of the medium in which the Sites are accessed by a user (such as through a web or mobile browser).

**The Information We Collect**

Matilda Jane Clothing may collect different types of information from you when you use or navigate the Sites. 

**_Anonymous Information Collected by Matilda Jane Clothing_** **.** When you visit the Sites, Matilda Jane Clothing will capture certain anonymous information about your visit that may not by itself reasonably identify you as the source (collectively, “Usage Information”). Usage Information includes your Internet provider's name (e.g., AOL), "click stream" activity such as when you click on a banner advertisement, your IP address, the type of Internet browser you are using, the location from which you are visiting the Sites, the type of computer operating system you are using to access the Sites, the domain name of the website from which you linked to the Sites, or the areas of the Site you visited and the actions you performed on the Sites. We will take reasonable measures to ensure that the Usage Information we collect is not personally identifiable and may not later be easily used to identify you except as may be required by applicable law.

**_Personal Information Collected by Matilda Jane Clothing_**  
We may collect personally identifiable information about you, such as your name, address, telephone number, email address, and financial information, such as financial account information or credit card numbers, and customer account log-in information, such as usernames and passwords (collectively, “Personal Information”). 

**_How We Collect Information_**

**_Directly from You_** **.** We may collect Personal Information from you when you voluntarily provide Personal Information to us by, for example, completing various forms on our Sites, creating a customer user account, or sending messages to Trunk Keepers. We also may collect Personal Information from you through our Sites when you voluntarily provide it to us through our Sites when signing up for our e-newsletter or other email communications, making a purchase, or inquiring about hosting a Trunk Show or becoming a Trunk Keeper. 

**_Through Your Use of the Sites._** We may record Usage Information that your browser transmits when you visit our Sites. We also may collect Usage Information about how you access and interact with the Sites through the use of automated tracking technology, such as “cookies,” and by reviewing web server log files. A cookie is a small data file that is transferred to a web browser, which enables our Sites to remember and customize your subsequent visit. Most Internet browsers automatically accept cookies. You can instruct your browser to block the acceptance of cookies or to provide you with a warning prompt before you accept cookies from our Sites. Please refer to your Internet browser’s instructions to learn more about these functions. If you reject cookies, the functionality of the Sites may be limited, and you may not be able to participate in several of the Sites’ features. Cookies are used as part of our statistical reporting on website usage activities; we do not capture any Personal Information through our use of cookies. 

**_From Third Parties_**. From time to time, we may receive information about you from third-party information brokers that have aggregated such information from various sources, such as other retailers with whom you have shopped, which we may use for Matilda Jane Clothing’s marketing purposes. 

**_How We Use and Disclose Information_**

**_General Uses and Disclosures_**. Matilda Jane Clothing may use your Personal Information and Usage Information for a variety of purposes, including, but not limited to, directly contacting you in response to your inquiries; processing your transactions and fulfilling your orders; sending you information about your orders, mailing and emailing you promotional materials, catalogs, and other marketing communications, from which you may opt-out of receiving; researching the effectiveness of our marketing efforts; analyzing users’ browsing and usage activities and patterns in order to understand users’ interests and preferences with respect to our services and the Sites; conveying relevant information to our Trunk Keepers, and managing our everyday business needs. Matilda Jane Clothing supplements the Personal Information we collect with information from other sources to tailor our websites, products, and offerings to your needs.

Matilda Jane Clothing uses Usage Information to enhance the content of our Sites to provide you with a better website browsing experience in the future, to respond to customer inquiries and suggestions, and to ensure that you are exposed to special offers and products that are of interest to you. We may also share this non-identifiable Usage Information with third parties from time to time for business purposes. 

Matilda Jane Clothing may disclose your Personal Information to third parties that may assist us with managing our daily operations, such as processing payments and providing general customer services. When you make a purchase on our website or via a Trunk Keeper, we request Personal Information—specifically, we request financial information, such as account or credit card numbers. We will use your financial information to bill you for products and services or otherwise process your transactions. By making a purchase on our website, you consent that we may provide your financial information to our service providers and to such third parties as we determine is necessary to process your transactions. These third parties may include the credit card processing company, our website provider, credit card network (such as Visa, American Express or Master Card) and banking institutions used to process the transaction.

Matilda Jane Clothing may also share your Personal Information with certain independent contractors, vendors, and suppliers with whom we contract to provide specific services and products related to our websites or our business, such as hosting and maintaining our websites, blog, providing credit card processing and fraud screening, operating activities on our behalf, authorizing credit card transactions, and developing applications for our Sites and email services. We limit our disclosure of your Personal Information to these third parties to the minimum information reasonably necessary for them to perform limited functions on our behalf. 

**_Opting Out of Email Communications._** If you have provided your email address to Matilda Jane Clothing, from time to time you will receive emails from us with information and offers from Matilda Jane Clothing and other companies that we feel would be of interest to you. With every commercial email, we will provide you with a link to opt-out from receiving future commercial emails. You may also opt-out of receiving future email messages from us by emailing us at CustomerCare@MatildaJaneClothing.com. Opt-out requests are usually handled as soon as the request is made. However, it may take up to ten (10) calendar days to process an opt-out request. If you wish to opt out from a communication sent by a specific Trunk Keeper, please reply to that Trunk Keeper with “Unsubscribe” in the subject line.

Because we want to ensure that those people who have opted out no longer receive commercial email from us, we may share the email addresses of our customers who have opted out of receiving commercial email with our trusted third-party advertising partners (such as Trunk Keepers) who engage in email marketing to their customers on our behalf. Therefore, we may share the email addresses of persons who have opted out with these third parties for the sole purpose of ensuring that the third parties have scrubbed their email marketing lists to remove the email addresses of those persons who have opted to no longer receive our commercial email announcements.

Please note that if you elect not to receive commercial email messages from us, we will continue to send you transactional related email, such as product recall information, safety or security information, subscription information, membership details, account status, order confirmations, shipping confirmations, invoices and customer-service related email.

Matilda Jane Clothing will not share your email address with any third party except as expressly set forth in this policy or unless you have requested or consented to such disclosure.

**_Opting Out of Offline Communications_**. When you provide Personal Information, such as your name, address and telephone number to us, we may use this information to contact you with correspondence and promotional offers from Matilda Jane Clothing. You always have the opportunity to choose to no longer receive these communications from us by emailing us at CustomerCare@MatildaJaneClothing.com.

**_Opting Out of Offline Communications From Other Companies_**. We will never share your Personal Information, such as your address and telephone number, with any third party, other than independent Trunk Keepers. If you wish to not receive postal mail from Trunk Keepers, please contact that Trunk Keeper directly using the information they provide.

**_Law Enforcement, Safety, and Legal Processes_** **.** We may share your Personal Information and/or Usage Information with law enforcement or other government officials if it relates to a criminal investigation or alleged criminal activity. We may also disclose specific Personal Information and/or Usage Information if required or permitted to do so by law, and we have a good-faith belief that disclosure is necessary to comply with applicable law or protect and defend the interests or safety of Matilda Jane Clothing or its employees, our Trunk Keepers, other visitors to our Sites, or a member of the public. We may also disclose your information to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, subpoena, or legal process. 

**_Sale or Acquisition of Assets_**. In the extraordinary event we become involved in a transaction involving the sale of our assets, such as a merger or acquisition, or if the Sites are transferred to another company, we may disclose and/or transfer your Personal Information as part of the transaction. If we are not the surviving entity in that transaction, the surviving entity may use your Personal Information pursuant to its own privacy policies and practices, which may differ from this Privacy Policy. 

**_Other Provisions_**

**_Policy for Individuals Under 13_**. The Matilda Jane Clothing websites are not intended for persons under the age of 13\. We do not market to and do not knowingly collect any Personal Information from or about a child under the age of 13 without the consent of the child’s parent or legal guardian. No information should be submitted or posted on our Sites by children under the age of 13. If we discover that we have inadvertently collected information from a child under 13 years of age, we will promptly take all reasonable measures to delete such information from our systems. 

**_Security of Your Information_**. Matilda Jane Clothing values your privacy and the security of your information. We utilize firewalls, secure access storage facilities and other industry standards to protect against the loss, misuse or alteration of your personal information. Our Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) software is the industry standard and among the best software available today for secure online commerce transactions. It encrypts all of your personal information, including credit card number, name and address, to protect the privacy of your information as it travels over the Internet. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we are committed to protecting your information, we cannot ensure or warrant that Personal Information will be completely secure from misappropriation by hackers or from other nefarious or criminal activities, or in the event of a failure of computer hardware, software, or a telecommunications network. We will notify you in the event we become aware of a security breach involving your personally identifiable information (as defined by the applicable state and federal laws) stored by or for us. By disclosing your email address to us for any reason, you expressly consent to receive electronic notice from us in the event of such a security breach.

**_Your California Privacy Rights_**. California law provides that California residents have a right to request businesses to tell them how their personal information has been shared, if at all, with third parties for the third parties’ direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please contact us at the contact information listed below.

**_Do Not Track_**. Certain web browsers and other devices you may use to access the Sites may permit you to indicate your preference that you do not wish to be “tracked” online. At this time, the Site does not respond to "Do Not Track" signals. 

**_Related Sites and Hyperlinks to Other Websites_**. Matilda Jane Clothing websites may include links to websites of other companies unaffiliated with Matilda Jane Clothing. Please note that we are unable to review all such sites and take no responsibility for their content. Our Privacy Policy will no longer be in effect once you leave our websites. Your use of an external website or any informational content found on an external websites is subject to and governed by the terms and guidelines of those website(s). We do not endorse or make any representations or warranties concerning, and will not in any way be liable for, any informational content, products, services, software, or other materials available on an external website, even if one or more pages of the external websites are framed within a page of our Sites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such websites or for the privacy policies and practices of other third parties including Independent Trunk Keepers. 

**_Accessing Your Information_**. Matilda Jane Clothing gives you the opportunity to remove or change personal information that you have provided to us or modify your preferences. This can be done by emailing us at [CustomerCare@MatildaJaneClothing.com](mailto:Customer.Care@MatildaJaneClothing.com).  
If you prefer to contact Matilda Jane Clothing by regular postal mail, please write to:

Matilda Jane Clothing   
ATTN: Customer Care Privacy  
3619 Centennial Drive  
Fort Wayne, IN 46808  
Please use the address provided by your Trunk Keeper for any Trunk Keeper related communications; all other inquiries should be directed to the address above.

**_Special Note about Trunk Keepers_**. Trunk Keepers are independent affiliates of Matilda Jane Clothing. They go through detailed training; however, they wholly own their business and utilize the tools we provide such as an email program, their administrative website, and other benefits. Trunk Keepers report to other Trunk Keepers who will have access to your information, excluding credit card information. We make every effort to ensure that Trunk Keepers operate their business in accordance with our policies: however, as they are independent business owners, we are not liable for their business practices and do not offer a remedy if they should break the published rules in the Matilda Jane Trunk Keeper Handbook.

**_Changes to This Policy_**. Please note this Privacy Policy may be changed from time to time in our sole and absolute discretion to reflect changes in our business practices. If we revise the Privacy Policy, we will notify you by posting the updated Privacy Policy Statement on the Sites. Changes to the Privacy Policy will become effective and will apply to the information collected starting on the date we post the revised Privacy Policy on the Sites. Your continued use of the Sites after any change has become effective will constitute your acceptance of any change. Accordingly, we urge you to frequently review the Privacy Policy posted on our Sites. 

**_Questions_**. If you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Policy, please contact us at:  
Matilda Jane Clothing   
ATTN: Customer Care Privacy  
3619 Centennial Drive  
Fort Wayne, IN 46808  
(260) 424-3511 or [CustomerCare@MatildaJaneClothing.com](mailto:Customer.Care@MatildaJaneClothing.com).
